Can I ask you to please recall a time
هل يمكنني أن أطلب منكم أن تستعيدوا وقتا
when you really loved something --
أحببتم فيها شيئًا ما بصدق
a movie, an album, a song or a book --
فيلم أو ألبوم أو أنشودة أو كتاب
and you recommended it wholeheartedly
وقمتم بكل مشاعركم بترشيحها
to someone you also really liked,
لشخص ما أيضًا أحببتموه بشدة
and you anticipated that reaction, you waited for it,
وتوقعتم رد الفعل هذا وانتظرتموه
and it came back, and the person hated it?
وعاد إليكم مرة أخرى ولكن هذا الشخص كرهه
So, by way of introduction,
وبهذه التقدمة
that is the exact same state
إنها بالضبط نفس الحالة
in which I spent every working day of the last six years. (Laughter)
التي أقضي فيها كل يوم عمل لي خلال السنوات الست الماضية
I teach high school math.
إنني أدرس الرياضيات للمرحلة الثانوية
I sell a product to a market
إنني أبيع منتجًا لسوق
that doesn't want it, but is forced by law to buy it.
لا يريد هذا المنتج ولكنه مجبر على شراءه بقوة القانون
I mean, it's just a losing proposition.
إنه درب من-- إنه عرض خاسر
So there's a useful stereotype about students that I see,
توجد صورة نمطية مفيدة جدًا عن الطلاب الذين أراهم
a useful stereotype about you all.
صورة نمطية مفيدة عنكم جميعًا
I could give you guys
يمكنني أن أعطيكم يا شباب
an algebra-two final exam,
اختبار نهائي لجبر ٢
and I would expect no higher
ولن أتوقع أكثر من
than a 25 percent pass rate.
نسبة نجاح ٢٥٪
And both of these facts say less about you or my students
وهذه الحقائق لا تخبر الكثير عنكم أو عن طلابي
than they do about what we call math education
بقدر ما تخبرنا عن ما نطلق عليه تعليم الرياضيات
in the U.S. today.
في الولايات المتحدة اليوم
To start with, I'd like to break math down into two categories.
وفي بدء الحديث فإني أود تقسيم الرياضيات إلى قسمين
One is computation; this is the stuff you've forgotten.
أحدهما هو الحساب. وهذا هو الأشياء التي نسيتموها
For example, factoring quadratics with
على سبيل المثال، تحليل المعادلات التربيعية
leading coefficients greater than one.
ذات المعامل الأساس أكبر من واحد.
This stuff is also really easy to relearn,
هذه الأشياء أيضًا من السهل تعلمها مرة أخرى،
provided you have a really strong grounding
بشرط أن يكون لديك بالفعل تأسيس قوي
in reasoning. Math reasoning --
في التفكير، التفكير الرياضي.
we'll call it the application
سوف نسميه تطبيق
of math processes to the world around us --
العمليات الرياضية في الواقع المحيط بنا.
this is hard to teach.
وهذا يصعب تدريسه.
This is what we would love students to retain,
هذا ما نود أن يحفظه طلابنا،
even if they don't go into mathematical fields.
حتى ولم يتخصصوا في مجالات رياضية.
This is also something that, the way we teach it in the U.S.
وهناك أيضًا شيء وهو أن الطريقة التي تدرسها بها في الولايات المتحدة
all but ensures they won't retain it.
تفعل كل شيء إلا أن تؤكد حفظهم لها.
So, I'd like to talk about why that is,
ولهذا فسأتحدث عن لماذا هذا،
why that's such a calamity for society, what we can do about it
لماذا يعد هذا مصيبة للمجتمع وماذا يمكننا أن نفعل حيالها.
and, to close with, why this is an amazing time
وسأنهي بلماذا يعتبر هذا وقتا شيق
to be a math teacher.
لأن تكون مدرس رياضيات.
So first, five symptoms
فأولًا، خمسة أعراض
that you're doing math reasoning wrong
بأنك تفكر رياضيًا بشكل خاطيء
in your classroom.
في فصلك.
One is a lack of initiative; your students don't self-start.
الأول هو نقص المبادرة، إن طلابك لن يبدأوا وحدهم.
You finish your lecture block
إنك تنهي الشرح
and immediately you have five hands going up
وتجد في التو خمس أيادي قد ارتفعت
asking you to re-explain the entire thing at their desks.
تطلب منك أن تعيد الشرح بأكمله مرة أخرى لدى طاولاتهم.
Students lack perseverance.
إن الطلاب يفتقرون إلى المثابرة
They lack retention; you find yourself
يفتقرون إلى القدرة على الاحتفاظ، إنك تجد نفسك
re-explaining concepts three months later, wholesale.
تعيد شرح المفاهيم كلها مرة أخرى بعد 3 شهور، كالبيع بالجملة.
There's an aversion to word problems,
يوجد نفور من المسائل اللفظية
which describes 99 percent of my students.
والذي يعبر عن 99 بالمائة من طلابي
And then the other one percent
والواحد بالمائة الأخرى
is eagerly looking for the formula
يبحثون بحرص عن المعادلات
to apply in that situation.
التي يمكن تطبيقها في هذه الحالة.
This is really destructive.
إن هذا مدمر حقًا.
David Milch, creator of "Deadwood" and other amazing TV shows,
ديفيد ميلش مؤسس "ديدوود" وبرامج تلفزيونية أخرى شيقة
has a really good description for this.
لديه توصيف جيد لهذا.
He swore off creating
لقد أقسم أنه سوف يصنع
contemporary drama,
دراما معاصرة
shows set in the present day,
مجموعة عروض في يومنا الحاضر
because he saw that when people fill their mind
لأنه لاحظ أنه حينما يملأ الناس عقولهم
with four hours a day of, for example, "Two and a Half Men," no disrespect,
بأربع ساعات يوميًا من، على سبيل المثال، "رجلين ونصف،" مع كل الاحترام،
it shapes the neural pathways, he said,
إنها تشكل المسارات العصبية كما قال.
in such a way that they expect simple problems.
بهذه الصورة هم يتوقعون مسائل ومشكلات سهلة.
He called it, "an impatience with irresolution."
لقد أسماها "عدم الصبر عند عدم القدرة على الحل"
You're impatient with things that don't resolve quickly.
إنك تكون غير صبور مع الأشياء التي لا تحل سريعًا
You expect sitcom-sized problems that wrap up in 22 minutes,
إنك تتوقع المشكلات الهزلية التي تنتهي في 22 دقيقة
three commercial breaks and a laugh track.
3 استراحات إعلانية ووصلة من الضحك.
And I'll put it to all of you,
وسأخبركم بها جميعًا
what you already know, that no problem worth solving is that simple.
ما تعلمونه جميعًا هو أنه لا توجد مسألة تستحق الحل وتكون سهلة
I am very concerned about this
إنني مهتم بهذا جدًا،
because I'm going to retire in a world that my students will run.
لأنني سأتقاعد في عالم يفر فيه طلابي
I'm doing bad things
إنني أسيء إلى
to my own future and well-being
مستقبلي وبقائي
when I teach this way.
حينما أدرس بهذه الطريقة
I'm here to tell you that the way our textbooks -- particularly
إنني هنا لأخبركم أن الطريقة التي عليها كتبنا خصيصا
mass-adopted textbooks -- teach math reasoning
كتبنا الرائجة تعلم التفكير الرياضي
and patient problem solving,
والحل الصبور للمسائل والمشكلات
it's functionally equivalent to turning on "Two and a Half Men" and calling it a day.
إنها تحاكي تماما عرض "رجلين ونصف" وتسميته يوم.
(Laughter)
(تصفيق)
In all seriousness. Here's an example from a physics textbook.
بكل جدية، هذا مثال من كتاب للفيزياء.
It applies equally to math.
إنه ينطبق تماما على الرياضيات.
Notice, first of all here,
لاحظ أولا هنا
that you have exactly three pieces of information there,
أن لديك تمامًا 3 معلومات هناك
each of which will figure into a formula
والتي ستتحول جميعها إلى معادلات
somewhere, eventually,
في مكان ما في النهاية
which the student will then compute.
والتي سيقوم الطالب بحسابها.
I believe in real life.
أعتقد أن في الحياة الحقيقية
And ask yourself, what problem have you solved, ever,
واسأل نفسك، هل هناك أي مسألة أو مشكلة قمت بحلها أبدا
that was worth solving
والتي كانت تستحق الحل،
where you knew all of the given information in advance;
وكنت تعرف كل المعطيات مقدمًا،
where you didn't have a surplus of information and you had to filter it out,
أو لم يكن لديك زيادة معلومات واحتجت لأن تنتقي منها،
or you didn't have sufficient information
أو لم تكن لديك المعلومات الكافية،
and had to go find some.
وعليك أن تبحث عنها،
I'm sure we all agree that no problem worth solving is like that.
إنني متأكد أننا جميعا متفقين أنه ما من مشكلة تستحق الحل ستكون بهذه الصورة.
And the textbook, I think, knows how it's hamstringing students
والكتب الدراسية، فيما أعتقد، تعلم أنها تعيق الطلاب.
because, watch this, this is the practice problem set.
لأنها، إنظر إلى هذا، هذه مجموعة مسائل للتدريب
When it comes time to do the actual problem set,
حينما يأتي الوقت لكي نقوم بحل مجموعة المسائل فعلًا
we have problems like this right here
فإن لدينا مسائل كهذه هنا
where we're just swapping out numbers and tweaking the context a little bit.
حينما نبدل فقط الأرقام ونغير السياق قليلًا
And if the student still doesn't recognize the stamp this was molded from,
وإن لم يتمكن الطالب بعد من التعرف على أي القوالب تم طبع هذه المسألة
it helpfully explains to you
فإنها في الغالب تخبرك
what sample problem you can return to to find the formula.
أي مسألة مشابهة يمكنك العودة لها لمعرفة المعادلة.
You could literally, I mean this,
يمكن فعليًا، أقصد،
pass this particular unit without knowing any physics,
اجتياز هذه الجزئية تحديدا دون أن تعرف أي فيزياء،
just knowing how to decode a textbook. That's a shame.
فقط تعلم كيف تفك شفرة كتاب. وهذا مخزي.
So I can diagnose the problem a little more specifically in math.
أنا أستطيع تشخيص المشكلة أكثر خاصة في الرياضيات.
Here's a really cool problem. I like this.
هذه مسألة ممتعة جدًا. أنا أحبها.
It's about defining steepness and slope
إنها عن تحديد الانحدار والميل
using a ski lift.
باستخدام رافعة تزلج
But what you have here is actually four separate layers,
ولكن ما لدينا هنا هو حقيقة أربع طبقات منفصلة
and I'm curious which of you can see the four separate layers
وأنا أفكر حقيقة من منكم يمكنه أن يرى الطبقات الأربع
and, particularly, how when they're compressed together
وخاصة كيف حينما يتم ضغطها سويًا
and presented to the student all at once,
ويتم تقديمها للطلاب دفعة واحدة
how that creates this impatient problem solving.
كيف يخلق هذا الحل غير الصبور للمشكلات
I'll define them here: You have the visual.
سأعرفهم هنا. لدينا الصورة
You also have the mathematical structure,
ولدينا أيضًا الهيكل الرياضي
talking about grids, measurements, labels,
نتحدث عن خطوط وقياسات وعناوين
points, axes, that sort of thing.
نقاط ومحاور وأشياء من هذا القبيل
You have substeps, which all lead to what we really want to talk about:
لدينا الخطوات الجزئية التي تقود إلى ما نريد حقيقة أن نتحدث عنه،
which section is the steepest.
أي قسم هو الأكثر ميلًا
So I hope you can see.
آمل أن تستطيعوا الرؤية.
I really hope you can see how what we're doing here
آمل أن تستطيعوا أن تروا حقًا كيف، ما نفعله هنا
is taking a compelling question, a compelling answer,
هو أننا نواجه سؤالًا صعبًا وإجابة صعبة،
but we're paving a smooth, straight path
ولكننا نمهد طريقًا سهلًا ومستقيمًا
from one to the other
من واحد إلى الآخر
and congratulating our students for how well
ونهنيء طلابنا على مهارتهم
they can step over the small cracks in the way.
في اجتياز التصدعات الصغيرة في الطريق.
That's all we're doing here.
هذا كل ما نفعله هنا.
So I want to put to you that if we can separate these in a different way
فما أريد أن أنقله إليكم هو أنه إن أمكننا أن نفصل هذه بطرق مختلفة
and build them up with students,
ونبنيها تدريجيًا مع الطلاب
we can have everything we're looking for in terms of patient problem solving.
يمكننا أن نحصل على كل ما نريده فيما يتعلق بالحل الصبور للمشكلات
So right here I start with the visual,
فهنا أنا سأبدأ بالصورة
and I immediately ask the question:
ومباشرة أسأل السؤال:
Which section is the steepest?
أي هذه الأقسام الأكثر ميلًا؟
And this starts conversation
وهذا يبدا حوارًا
because the visual is created in such a way where you can defend two answers.
لأن الصورة تم إعدادها بطريقة يمكنك معها أن تدافع عن إجابتين
So you get people arguing against each other,
وبالتالي يبدأ الناس في الجدال سويًا
friend versus friend,
صديق في مقابل صديق
in pairs, journaling, whatever.
أزواجًا .كتابة. أي شيء
And then eventually we realize
وفي النهاية ندرك
it's getting annoying to talk about
أنه من المتعب أن نتحدث عن
the skier in the lower left-hand side of the screen
المتزلج في الجزء السفلي الأيسر من الشاشة
or the skier just above the mid line.
أو المتزلج فوق خط النصف مباشرة
And we realize how great would it be
وندرك كيف سيكون رائعًا
if we just had some A, B, C and D labels
لو كان لدينا بعض ترقيم أ، ب،ج،د
to talk about them more easily.
لنشير إليها بشكل أسهل
And then as we start to define what does steepness mean,
وعندها حينما نبدأ في تعريف ما معنى الانحدار
we realize it would be nice to have some measurements
سندرك أنه سيكون لطيفًا لو كان لدينا بعض المقاييس
to really narrow it down, specifically what that means.
بحيث نقلل الخيارات قدر الإمكان وخاصة ماذا يعني هذا.
And then and only then,
وحينئد وفقط حينئذ
we throw down that mathematical structure.
نطرح هذا الهيكل الرياضي
The math serves the conversation,
الرياضيات تخدم الحوار.
the conversation doesn't serve the math.
الحوار لا يخدم الرياضيات.
And at that point, I'll put it to you that nine out of 10 classes
وإننا في هذه النقطة، سأعلنها لكم أن 9 من 10 فصول
are good to go on the whole slope, steepness thing.
ماهرين للحديث عن ما يتعلق بموضوع الانحدار والميل
But if you need to,
ولكن إن أردت،
your students can then develop those substeps together.
فإن طلابك يمكنهم بناء هذه الخطوات الجزئية سويًا.
Do you guys see how this, right here, compared to that --
هل ترون كيف هذه هنا مقارنة بهذه
which one creates that patient problem solving, that math reasoning?
أي من هذه يخلق الحل الصبور للمشكلات والمسائل؟ أيها يخلق التفكير الرياضي؟
It's been obvious in my practice, to me.
إنه لجلي بالنسبة لي في ممارستي
And I'll yield the floor here for a second to Einstein,
وسوف أترك الساحة هنا لثانية لأينشتاين
who, I believe, has paid his dues.
والذي أعتقد بأنه قد أدى ما عليه
He talked about the formulation of a problem being so incredibly important,
لقد تحدث عن أن صياغة المشكلة مهمة لدرجة بالغة
and yet in my practice, in the U.S. here,
ولكن من واقع ممارستي، هنا في الولايات المتحدة
we just give problems to students;
إنما نعطي الطلاب فقط المسائل والمشكلات
we don't involve them in the formulation of the problem.
إننا لا نشركهم معنا في تكوين المشكلة أوالمسألة
So 90 percent of what I do
وبهذا فإن 90% مما أفعله
with my five hours of prep time per week
في الخمس ساعات أسبوعيًا التي أقضيها في التحضير
is to take fairly compelling elements
أن آخذ عناصر تشمل تحديًا معتدلًا
of problems like this from my textbook
لمسائل كهذه من كتابي
and rebuild them in a way that supports math reasoning and patient problem solving.
وأعيد بنائهم مرة أخرى بطريقة تدعم التفكير الرياضي والحل الصبور للمسائل والمشكلات.
And here's how it works.
وفيما يلي كيف أفعل هذا.
I like this question. It's about a water tank.
أنا أحب هذا السؤال. إنه عن خزان مياة.
The question is: How long will it take you to fill it up?
السؤال هو: كم من الوقت ستستغرق لكي تملؤه بالماء؟ حسنًا؟
First things first, we eliminate all the substeps.
الأشياء المهمة أولًا، نقول بإزالة الخطوات الجزئية.
Students have to develop those,
يجب على الطلاب بناء هذه.
they have to formulate those.
يجب عليهم صياغتها.
And then notice that all the information written on there is stuff you'll need.
ثم لاحظ أن كل المعلومات المكتوبة هنا هي معلومات تحتاج إليها.
None of it's a distractor, so we lose that.
لا يوجد أي منها ما يشتت الانتباه، وهذا يفقدنا
Students need to decide, "All right, well,
أن على الطلاب أن يقرروا، حسنا
does the height matter? Does the side of it matter?
هل الارتفاع يؤثر؟ هل الحجم يؤثر؟
Does the color of the valve matter? What matters here?"
هل لون الصمام يؤثر؟ ما الذي يؤثر هنا؟
Such an underrepresented question in math curriculum.
هذا السؤال الذي لم يحسن تقديمه في منهج الرياضيات.
So now we have a water tank.
والآن لدينا خزان مياة
How long will it take you to fill it up? And that's it.
كم من الوقت ستستغرق لكي تملؤه، وهذا كل ما هنالك.
And because this is the 21st century
ولأن هذا هو القرن الحادي والعشرين،
and we would love to talk about the real world on its own terms,
وسنحب أن نتكلم عن العالم الحقيقي بمفرداته الخاصة
not in terms of line art or clip art
وليس بمفردات الكرتون أو الرسوم
that you so often see in textbooks,
والتي كثيرا ما تراها في الكتب الدراسية،
we go out and we take a picture of it.
نخرج ونلتقط له صورة.
So now we have the real deal.
والآن لدينا الشيء حقيقة
How long will it take it to fill it up?
كم سنستغرق لكي نملؤه؟
And then even better is we take a video,
وربما يكون من الأفضل أن نلتقط فيديو.
a video of someone filling it up.
فيديو لشخص ما يملأ الخزان.
And it's filling up slowly, agonizingly slowly.
ولو كان الملء بطيئًا بطيئًا بشكل موجع
It's tedious.
فإنها عملية جد مرهقة.
Students are looking at their watches, rolling their eyes,
الطلاب ينظرون في ساعاتهم وأعينهم تدور
and they're all wondering at some point or another,
وكلهم يتساءلون بين حين وآخر
"Man, how long is it going to take to fill up?"
"إلهي، كم من الوقت سيستغرق لكي يملؤه؟"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
That's how you know you've baited the hook, right?
وبهذا ستعرف أنك قد أعددت الطعم جيدًا للصيد
And that question, off this right here, is really fun for me
وهذا السؤال هنا بعيدًا عن هذا يبدو ممتعًا جدًا لي
because, like the intro,
لأنه كما سبق في المقدمة
I teach kids -- because of my inexperience --
إنني أدرس الأطفال بسبب عدم خبرتي
I teach the kids that are the most remedial, all right?
أدرس الأطفال الأسهل علاجًا بكل سهولة.
And I've got kids who will not join a conversation about math
ولدي أطفال لن يشاركوا أبدا في حوار عن الرياضيات
because someone else has the formula;
لأن شخص آخر لديه المعادلة
someone else knows how to work the formula better than me,
شخص آخر يعرف كيف يستخدم المعادلة بشكل أفضل مني.
so I won't talk about it.
ولهذا فلن أتكلم عنها.
But here, every student is on a level playing field of intuition.
ولكن هنا الجميع بشكل ما يمارس أحد أنواع البديهة
Everyone's filled something up with water before,
الجميع سبق له وأن ملأ شيء ما بالماء
so I get kids answering the question, "How long will it take?"
وبهذا أحصل على إجابة الأطفال كم من الوقت ستستغرق.
I've got kids who are mathematically and conversationally intimidated
لقد جعلت أطفال لديهم خوف من الرياضيات أو حتى من المحادثة
joining the conversation.
ينضمون للحوار
We put names on the board, attach them to guesses,
لإننا نضع الأسماء على السبورة ونربطها بتخمينات
and kids have bought in here.
والأطفال اقتنعوا بذلك.
And then we follow the process I've described.
وبعدها نتبع العملية التي وصفتها.
And the best part here, or one of the better parts
وأفضل جزء هنا أو من أفضل الأجزاء
is that we don't get our answer from the answer key
هو أننا لا نحصل على الإجابة من مفتاح الإجابات
in the back of the teacher's edition.
في نهاية نسخة المعلم
We, instead, just watch the end of the movie.
إننا بدلًا من ذلك نشاهد نهاية الفيلم
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And that's terrifying,
وهذا مخيف، حسنًا.
because the theoretical models that always work out
لأن النماذج النظرية التي دومًا ما تكون متسقة مع
in the answer key in the back of a teacher's edition,
مفتاح الإجابات في نهاية نسخة المعلم،
that's great, but
هذا عظيم ولكن
it's scary to talk about sources of error
إنه من المخيف التحدث عن مصادر الخطأ
when the theoretical does not match up with the practical.
عندما لا يتفق النظري مع العملي
But those conversations have been so valuable,
ولكن هذه الحوارات كانت قيمة جدًا
among the most valuable.
ومن بين الأقيم حقًا.
So I'm here to report some really fun games
وعليه فأنا هنا لكي أتحدث عن بعض المكاسب الممتعة
with students who come pre-installed
مع الطلاب الذي يأتون مصابين
with these viruses day one of the class.
بهذه الفيروسات في اليوم الأول من الدراسة
These are the kids who now, one semester in,
وهؤلاء هم الأطفال الذين وبعد فصل دراسي واحد
I can put something on the board,
يمكنني أن أضع شيئًا ما على السبورة
totally new, totally foreign,
جديد تمامًا ولم يسمعوا به من قبل
and they'll have a conversation about it for three or four minutes more
وسيبدأوا في الحديث عنه لمدة ثلاث أو أربع دقائق أكثر
than they would have at the start of the year,
مما كانوا سيفعلون في بداية السنة،
which is just so fun.
والذي يبدو رائع حقًا.
We're no longer averse to word problems,
لم نعد نكره المسائل اللفظية
because we've redefined what a word problem is.
لأننا أعدنا تعريف المسائل اللفظية
We're no longer intimidated by math,
لم نعد نخاف من الرياضيات،
because we're slowly redefining what math is.
لأننا وببطء نعيد تعريف ما هي الرياضيات.
This has been a lot of fun.
وهذا كان شيقًا جدًا.
I encourage math teachers I talk to to use multimedia,
إنني أشجع مدرسي الرياضيات الذين أتحدث معهم على استخدام الوسائط المتعددة،
because it brings the real world into your classroom
لأنها تحضر الواقع المحيط إلى داخل الفصل
in high resolution and full color;
بدقة عالية وبألوان جذابة
to encourage student intuition for that level playing field;
لأن يشجعوا بداهة الطلاب لهذا المستوى
to ask the shortest question you possibly can
لأن تسأل أقصر أسئلة يمكنك طرحها
and let those more specific questions come out in conversation;
وأن تترك هذه الأسئلة الأكثر تفصيلًا لتكون وليدة المحادثة،
to let students build the problem,
أن نجعل الطلاب ينشئوا هم المسألة
because Einstein said so;
لأن أينشتاين قال هذا
and to finally, in total, just be less helpful,
وأخيرًا وإجمالًا ابذل قدر أقل من المساعدة
because the textbook is helping you in all the wrong ways:
لأن الكتاب الدراسي يساعدك بكل الطرق الخاطئة
It's buying you out of your obligation,
إنه يساعدك فقط لالتزامك تجاه
for patient problem solving and math reasoning, to be less helpful.
أن تجعل الحل الصبور للمسائل والتفكير الرياضي أقل فائدة.
And why this is an amazing time to be a math teacher right now
ولماذا هذا يعد وقتًا رائعًا لأن تكون مدرس رياضيات الآن
is because we have the tools to create
لأنه لدينا الأدوات لنبني
this high-quality curriculum in our front pocket.
منهجًا دراسيًا عالي الجودة في جيوبنا الأمامية.
It's ubiquitous and fairly cheap,
إنه متاح في كل مكان ورخيص نوعًا ما.
and the tools to distribute it
والأدوات لكي توزعه
freely under open licenses
بحرية وبتراخيص مفتوحة
has also never been cheaper or more ubiquitous.
لم تكن أيضًا أرخص من ذلك ولا أكثر توافرًا
I put a video series on my blog not so long ago
لقد وضعت سلسلة فيديو على مدونتي من وقت ليس ببعيد
and it got 6,000 views in two weeks.
وتم مشاهدته 6000 مرة في أسبوعين.
I get emails still from teachers in countries I've never visited
تصلني رسائل بريد إلكتروني من معلمين في بلدان لم أزرها من قبل
saying, "Wow, yeah. We had a good conversation about that.
يقولون "رائع، نعم، لقد لقد كانت لنا محادثة ممتعة حول هذا.
Oh, and by the way, here's how I made your stuff better,"
"وعلى فكرة، هذا هو كيف أمكنني تحسين من تفعله بشكل أكبر"
which, wow.
رائع
I put this problem on my blog recently:
لقد وضعت هذه المسألة على مدونتي مؤخرًا
In a grocery store, which line do you get into,
في متجر تجزئة، في أي الخطوط تقف؟
the one that has one cart and 19 items
في الخط الذي به عربة تسوق واحدة و19 من المشتريات
or the line with four carts and three, five, two and one items.
أو الخط الذي به 4 عربات تسوق وثلاثة وخمسة وواحد من المشتريات.
And the linear modeling involved in that was some good stuff for my classroom,
والنموذج الخطي المعني بهذا كان شيئًا جميلًا بالنسبة لفصلي
but it eventually got me on "Good Morning America" a few weeks later,
ولكنها تدريجيًا أدت لظهوري على "صباح الخير أميريكا" بعد ذلك بأسابيع قليلة،
which is just bizarre, right?
والذي يعد غريبًا
And from all of this, I can only conclude
ومن كل هذا يمكنني فقط أن استخلص
that people, not just students,
أن الناس وليس فقط الطلاب
are really hungry for this.
يتوقون إلى هذا بشكل كبير
Math makes sense of the world.
الرياضيات تجعل العالم له معنى
Math is the vocabulary
الرياضيات هي بمثابة مفردات اللغة
for your own intuition.
لبديهتك الخاصة.
So I just really encourage you, whatever your stake is in education --
وبهذا فأنا أشجعكم أيما كان دورك في التعليم
whether you're a student, parent, teacher, policy maker, whatever --
سواء كنت طالبًا أو ولي أمر أو مدرس أو صانع سياسة أو أي شيء آخر
insist on better math curriculum.
فلتصر على منهج رياضيات أفضل.
We need more patient problem solvers. Thank you. (Applause)
إننا نحتاج لمن يقومون بحل المسائل والمشكلات بشكل أكثر صبرًا. شكرًا لكم.